SAA Annual Meeting Audio Recordings 6086 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
SAA Annual Meeting Audio Recordings
1994-2010
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Society of American Archivists (SAA)
6086 AV
25.94 cubic feet
23.5 linear ft.
Audio recordings.
Audiocassettes of selected sessions from annual meetings. Where available, a program is also included.
7988421
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 12, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 25, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Archives; Society of American Archivists.
7988421
- Annual Meeting Programs, 1997-199; 1 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1999; 1997
- SAA - Washington, DC Convention Recordings Index --, 2001; 2 (Box 1)
- 67th Annual Meeting Spotlight on Archives, 2003; 3 (Box 1)
- Preliminary Program -- Archival Roots: Our Foundation and Our Future -- 66th Annual Meeting - August 19-25, 2002, 4 (Box 1)
- SAA - 58th Annual Meeting - Conference List, 1994; 5 (Box 1)
- 1998 Annual Meeting - August 31-September 6, 6 (Box 1)
- 64th Annual Meeting - Denver 2000 - The Pre-Eminent Event for Archives Professionals -- August 28-September 3, 2000, Denver, Colorado, 7 (Box 1)
- August 5-7, 2004 Meeting (1-3) (Box 5)
- 2006 Meeting (1-3) (Box 6)
- Aug. 29-Sept 1, 2007 Meeting (1-3) (Box 7)
- Aug. 28-30, 2008 (1-3) (Box 8)
- Aug. 13-15, 2009 (1-4) (Box 9)
- Aug. 13-15, 2010 (1-3) (Box 10)
- Taking Car of Business: New approaches to Business Records (Box 11)
  Tape 1 of 2
- Taking Care of Business: New Approaches to Business Records (Box 12)
  Tape 2 of 2
- Sound Solutions: Decision Making for manuscripts Repositories with Audio Recordings (Box 13)
- Sound Solution: (Box 14)
- Assessing Access Options: Copies, Fiche, of Disc? (Box 15)
- Assessing Access Options: (Box 16)
- Building for Preservation Considerations in the Design 7 Construction of Facilities (Box 17)
- Building for Preservation Considerations (Box 18)
- Who's Using What: Current Research on the Use of Archives (Box 19)
- Who's Using What: (Box 20)
- Providing Access to Oral History Interviews (Box 21)
- Providing Access to Oral History Interviews Chair: (Box 22)
- The Impact of Technology on the Research Process: Archives in the Year 2000 (Box 23)
- The Impact of Technology on the Research Process: (Box 24)
- What is a Record? (Box 25)
- What is a Record? (Box 26)
- Fugitives in the Archives: Standards of Documentation and Access for Oral Histories (Box 27)
- Fugitives in the Archives: (Box 28)
- Retrospective Conversion of Archival Records to Machine-Readable Form (Box 29)
- Retrospective Conversion of Archival Records to Machine-Readable Form: (Box 30)
- More Than Decoration: Moving Images, Sound Recordings, Oral Histories and Photographs as Documents for Historical Research (Box 31)
- More Than Decoration: (Box 32)
- Documenting Contemporary Social Protest Movements: (Box 33)
- Documenting Contemporary Social Protest Movements (Box 33)
- Preserve to Serve (Box 35)
- Preserve to Serve: (Box 36)
- Working Relationships: Implementing AMC in Local Systems (Box 37)
- Working Relationships: (Box 38)
- Subject Access to Archival & Manuscript (Box 39)
- Subject Access to Archival & Manuscript Collection Chair (Box 40)
- Standards for Archival Description (Box 41)
- Standards for Archival Description: (Box 42)
- Are We What People Think We Keep? (Box 43)
- Are We What People Think We Keep? (Box 43)
- 2020 Vision: (Box 44)
- 2020 Vision: Recap (Box 45)
- Of Cabbages & Kings: Learning to Manage Up (Box 47)
- Archivists and the Law (Box 48)
- 212 Choosing Records Management Software (Box 49)
- 2020 Vision: Trends in Research (Box 50)
- Premises, Promises, Problems: Practicing Archives with a Postmodern Perspective (Box 51)
- Premises, Promises, Problems: (Box 52)
- Videodisc Technology & Visual Image Collections (Box 53)
- Videodisc Technology & Visual Image Collections: (Box 54)
- Preservation Program Evaluation: Report on the Finding (Box 55)
- Preservation Program Evaluation: (Box 56)
- Data Base Management Systems for Microcomputers (Box 57)
- Data Base Management Systems for Microcomputers: (Box 58)
- The Information Chain: A National Integrated Data Base (Box 59)
- The Information Chain: (Box 60)
- The Archival Administration of Electronic Records (Box 61)
- The Archival Administration of Electronic Records: (Box 62)
- Electronic Records Policy Frameworks (Box 63)
- Electronic Records Policy Frameworks: (Box 64)
- Web Sites, Electronic Finding Aids and the Archival Researcher (Box 65)
- Web Sites, Electronic Finding Aids and the Archival Researcher (Box 66)
- 2020 Vision: Technology Trends (Box 67)
- 2020 Vision: (Box 68)
- Is There Archival Theory? (Box 69)
- Is There Archival Theory? (Box 70)
- 2020 Vision: Organizational Trends (Box 71)
- 2020 Vision: (Box 72)
- Keeping Up with MARC AMC (Box 73)
- Keeping Up with MARC AMC Presenters: (Box 74)
- Archives and the Law (Box 75)
- Archivists and the Law Chair: Chris Paton (Box 76)
- Assessing and Purchasing Preservation Microfilming Services (Box 77)
- 2020 Vision: Trends in Research (Box 78)
- Planning a High Performance Library (Box 79)
- Muddying the Waters: When the Law Dictates Archival Decisions (Box 80)
- Archival Entrepreneurs: Donor Support for Archival Collections (Box 81)
- Information Seeking Behaviors: Implications for Archives, Organizations, and System Designers (Box 82)
- Proactive Collecting: Collaborating with Modern Photographers (Box 83)
- Standards for Encoding of Digital Archival Objects (Box 84)
- Show me the Money: Marketing and Licensing Graphic Materials and Ephemera (Box 85)
- Putting Audio and Moving Images on the Web (Box 86)
- Diversity Initiatives (Box 87)
- Depicting, Documenting and Deconstructing Industrial and Post-Industrial Society (Box 88)
- Cooperation/Competition: Strategies for Dealing with Contemporary Business Records (Box 89)
- The Security of Archival Records: Learning from Recent Events (Box 90)
- Selling Security to Management, Staff and Researchers (Box 91)
- The Changing Nature of Documentation & Its Impact on Historical Research (Box 92)
- Defining "Better": Evaluating Progress in Appraisal (Box 93)
- Defining "Better": Evaluating Progress in Appraisal (Box 94)
- Depicting, Documenting and Deconstructing Industrial and Post-Industrial Society (Box 95)
- Recent Developments in Copyright Law: Overview and Impact (Box 96)
- Lessons in Sportsmanship for Archivists Learned from Wrestling with the IRS Records Bear (Box 97)
- The Paper Chase: The Old Perils and the New Rewards of Collecting the Papers of Lawyers and Judges (Box 98)
- To Put Out a Fire: Fire Suppression Options for the Millennium (Box 99)
- Administering Privacy and Confidentiality in Sensitive Records (Box 100)
- Diversity Initiatives (Box 101)
- Undaunted by the Deluge: Case Studies in Managing an Archives Backlog -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 102)
- More Bang for Your Buck: Evolving Standards in Archival Description -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 103)
- Clearing Copyright: An International Archival Perspective -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 104)
- Collaborative Digital Imaging Projects: Does Everyone Get What They Expected? -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 105)
- Real Research on Real Users -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 106)
- Records of Patients and Human Subjects: Access to Sensitive Materials -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 107)
- Philadelphia Criminal Court Records Sampling Project: Case Study in Archival Sampling Design & Implement -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 108)
- Everything But Encoding: Costs and Benefits of EAD Consortia -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 28-Sept. 3, 2000 (Box 109)
- Managing and Using Web Sites in Archives and Records Management -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept. 2, 2001 (Box 110)
- Making History Real: New Insights on Using Primary Sources in the Classroom -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept. 2, 2001 (Box 111)
- Seek and Ye Shall Find? Information Seeking Behavior and the Archives -- -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 112)
- In Search of Labor's Lost Treasures: The Archivist's Collaborative Role in Documenting & Preserving Labor's Material -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 113)
- Data Storage and Migration -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 114)
- Archival Practice and the Authenticity of Photographs -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 115)
- You Can Run But You Can't Hide: meeting the Challenges of Access to Nontraditional Archival Records -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 116)
- To EAD or Not To EAD-Is That Really the Question? -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 117)
- Open or closed Collections? Creating Access Policies to Sensitive Materials -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 118)
- Panama Canal Records in Transition -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 119)
- Emulation as a Digital Preservation Strategy: An Empirical Test -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 120)
- Privacy, Confidentiality, and Ethical Considerations in Dealing with the Historical Records of Active Businesses -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 121)
- Moneychangers in the Temple: the Role of Fundraising in Collection Development -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 122)
- Real-World Strategies for the Management and Preservation of Digital Records -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 123)
- The Internationalization of EAD, a Clash with Descriptive Standards? -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 124)
- An Odyssey to the Future: Building the Electronic Records Archives -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 125)
- Archiving the Digital Age: Appraisal and Preservation of Web-Based Communications -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 126)
- Archivists as Digital Librarians -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 127)
- The Internet, Law and Ethics: The Dilemmas We Face -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 128)
- Electronic Records Tools for the Rest of Us: The Archivist's Workbench -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 129)
- EAD Implementation: Strategies for the Rest of Us -- The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 27-Sept.2, 2001 (Box 130)
- Managing Electronic Records in the Networked Office Environment (1 of 2) (Box 131)
- Managing Electronic Records in the Networked Office Environment (2 of 2) (Box 132)
- Managing Organizational Records on the World Wide Web: Making a Start (1 of 2) (Box 133)
- Managing Organizational Records on the World Wide Web: Making a Start (2 of 2) (Box 134)
- Copyright and Licensing in the Digital Age (1 of 2) (Box 135)
- Copyright and Licensing in the Digital Age (2 of 2) (Box 136)
- Virtual Libraries and Real Preservation: Coming to Terms with the Biggest Challenge (1 of 2) (Box 137)
- Virtual Libraries and Real Preservation: Coming to Terms with the Biggest Challenge (2 of 2) (Box 138)
- Bytes in the Research Room: Providing Reference Services for Electronic Records (1 of 2) (Box 139)
- Bytes in the Research Room: Providing Reference Services for Electronic Records (2 of 2) (Box 140)
- Environmental Monitoring: The Key to Long Term Preservation (1 of 2) (Box 141)
- Environmental Monitoring: The Key to Long Term Preservation (2 of 2) (Box 142)
- The Ethics of Collecting Personal Papers (1 of 2) (Box 143)
- The Ethics of Collecting Personal Papers (2 of 2) (Box 144)
- Exhibition and Preservation: An Uneasy Partnership (1 of 2) (Box 145)
- Exhibition and Preservation: An Uneasy Partnership (2 of 2) (Box 146)
- Archival Ethics in Practice (Box 147)
- Genius & the Mobocracy: Assessing Models for Archival Information System Architectures (Box 148)
- Feeding Undergraduate Researchers Without Becoming "Mc Archives" (Box 149)
- Capturing the fifteen Minutes: Collecting & Preserving Underground Culture (Box 150)
- Enhancing Access to the Archives Internet ably (Box 151)
- Enhancing Access to the Archives Internetably (Box 152)
- Encoded Archival Description: A Progress Report (Box 153)
- Encoded Archival Description: (Box 154)
- Giving Customers What They Want: Implementing Effect Access Services (Box 155)
- Giving Customers What They Want: (Box 156)
- Using SGML to Develop New Models of Electronic Historical Editions (Box 157)
- Using SGNL to Develop New Models of Electronic Historical Editions (Box 158)
- Use it or Lose it: Use as an Appraisal Tool? (Box 159)
- Use it or Lose it: (Box 160)
- Writing for Publication (Box 161)
- Writing for Publication, 1 (Box 162)
- Making Them Hear You: Archives & Publicity Chair - Elsie Freeman (Box 163)
- Making Them Hear You: (Box 164)
- Occupational Histories: Putting Them To Use (Box 165)
- Occupational Histories: Putting Them To Use Chair (Box 166)
- Fundamentals of Film & Microfilm Preservation (Box 167)
- Fundamentals of Film and Microfilm Preservation Chair (Box 168)
- Shop Talk: ?The Nuts and bolts of Reformatting Photographs for Preservation and Access (Box 169)
- Shop Talk: The Nuts and Bolts of Reformatting Photographs for Preservation and Access (Box 170)
- Managing Reference Service: Products & Possibilities (Box 171)
- Managing Reference Service: (Box 172)
- Genius & the Mobocracy: Assessing Models for Archival Information System Architectures (Box 173)
- Capturing the Fifteen Minutes: Collecting & Preserving Underground Culture (Box 174)
- Trends and Changes in Privacy and Confidentiality: A Discussion of the Impact of Technology, Law & Security The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 175)
- Professional Partnerships: Lawyers The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 176)
- Go Show It On the Mountain: Using primary Sources in Teaching The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 177)
- Planning a Preservation Re-recording Project for Sound Recordings The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 178)
- Challenges and Opportunities in Integrating Access The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 179)
- Administering Third-Party Privacy Rights in manuscript Collections The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 180)
- Intrinsic Value in Archives: a discussion The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 181)
- Partnering Against Crime: Working With Manuscript Dealers in Theft Investigations The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 182)
- Sticky Wickets: The Ethics of Equal Access, Sensitive Content and On-going Relationships The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 183)
- Going to the Source: Users and Archival Research The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 184)
- Revisiting the Electronic Records Research Agenda The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 185)
- Planning a Preservation Re-recording Project for Sound Recordings The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 186)
- Digital Preservation: Image Quality and Project Development The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 187)
- True Confessions: The Real Story Behind Image Scanning The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 22-24, 2002 (Box 188)
- Documenting Rosie: Archival Sources for the Study of Women and the Home Front During World War II The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 189)
- Archives Unplugged: Fundamentals of Moving Image Archives The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 190)
- Lost at Sea: navigating the Choppy Waters of Copyright Legislation The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 191)
- Archives Unplugged: Privacy and confidentiality 101 The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 192)
- Implementing Electronic Records Archives Today Using Available Technology The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 193)
- On Whose Terms?: Usability Issues and Online Archival Access Systems The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 194)
- To Have But Not to Hold: issues of Institutional and Private Ownership of E-Mail Records The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 195)
- Archival Reference in the 21st Century: Moving from Theory to Practice The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 196)
- Filling in the Margins: Documenting Extreme Social History The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 197)
- Digital Preservation: Longevity, Image Quality, and Metadata The Society of American Archivists held Aug. 20-24, 2003 (Box 198)
- Intellectural Property and the Archivists, 1994 (Box 199)
  SAA 58th Annual Meeting - Sept. 7-11, 1994
- Intellectual Property and the Archivists - Chair (Box 199)
- Intellectural Property and the Archivists - Chair: (Box 200)
- Preservation and Digitization of Photograph Collections (Box 201)
  Tape 1 of 2 SAA 58th Annual Meeting - Sept. 7-11, 1994
- Preservation and Digitization of Photograph Collections (Box 202)
  Tape 2 of 2 SAA 58th Annual Meeting - Sept. 7-11, 1994
- Protecting Legal Title: Using Abandoned Property Laws (Box 203)
- The Archival Core: Advocacy for the Future (Box 204)
- The Archival Core: Advocacy for the Future (Box 205)
- Recordkeeping Requirements and Electronic Information Systems: A Progress Report on the University of Pittsburg Project (Box 206)
- Recordkeeping Requirements and Electronic Information Systems: (Box 207)
- Sins of the Fathers: Conducting Reappraisal and Deaccessioning (Box 208)
- Sins of the Fathers: Conducting Reappraisal and Deaccessioning (Box 209)
- Without Consent: The Question of Third Party Privacy Rights in Collections of Personal Papers (Box 210)
- Without Consent: The Question of Third Party Privacy Rights in Collections of Personal Papers (Box 211)